Preliminary Guide to the Percy E. Ryberg Papers, [1910s]-1984
Percy E. Ryberg papers [1910s]-1984
Ryberg, Percy Edward, 1908-
2 Linear Feet 700 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Percy E. Ryberg Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2003.
Biographical Note
Physician of Swedish and English ancestry, well known in his specialties in psychiatry, which included gender identity and sexuality, sexual disorders, and alcoholism.
Collection Overview
The collection consists primarily of Ryberg's personal family correspondence (in particular with his wife, Barbara), journals, and other personal papers ([1910s]-1984). Also includes biographical and genealogical information; photographs and a photo album documenting Ryberg's travels through Germany and the United Kingdom, including a visit to the home of Rom Landau; professional correspondence and items illustrating aspects of his career, including the publication of his book, Health, Sex and Birth Control; and material documenting his youth in Argentina.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Ryberg, Percy Edward, 1908-.
Ryberg family
Landau, Rom, 1899-.
Psychiatrists
Psychiatry
Psychiatrists -- Correspondence
Argentina -- History
Germany -- Description and travel
Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Accessions 2003-0039 and 2003-0040
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Notebook, 1937-1938
    - Delegate's Handbook for the Conference on Church, Community, and State for the Universal Christian Council for Life and Work, Oxford, England, 1937 July 12-26
    - Diary No. 30, 1926 July-Oct.
    - Letters and clippings, 1940s-1980s
    - Diary No. 28, 1926 2 Feb. - 25 April
    - Genealogical information
    - Photographs, 1937, 1981
    - Personal Correspondence, 1910s-1970s
    - Biographical Sketch of Ryberg
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence including photographs, 1930s-1970s
    - Anchor Press
      Includes correspondence and legal information related to the publication of Ryberg's book, Health, Sex and Birth Control
    - Book sales
    - Salena Jones
    - Insurance File, 1960s-1970s
    - Correspondence and loan information
    - Correspondence including x-rays of Barbara Ryberg's knee, 1950s
    - Personal correspondence and news clippings, 1940s
    - Caribbean
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Professional correspondence, 1950s-1970s
    - Photograph of Ryberg with other doctors
    - Taylor family
      - Correspondence, 1960s-1984
    - Wedding Photographs
    - Personal correspondence and clippings, 1950s
    - Column Ideas, 1950s
    - Writing, Creative
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Photograph, undated
    - Photograph of Alcoholism in Industry Conference, 1971
    - Personal correspondence and clippings, 1930s-1940s
    - Address book
    - Diary No. 26, 1925, Aug.-Nov.
      Kept by Ryberg when he was a schoolboy in Argentina.
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Diploma from College of Physicians and Surgeons in Ontario, 1943, April 5
    - Photo album with postcards, 1937
      From locations including Munich, Derbyshire, Canterbury, Cambridge, London, Scotland, York, Durham, Windermere, Glasgow, Sunderland, and Edinburgh; includes photos of Rom Landau's house near Chichester, England.